A Guide to the William David Eppes Collection of Arts Memorabilia 1908-1998
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
The William David Eppes Collection of Arts Memorabilia 1908-1998
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10582-g
2310 items
This collection of ca. 2310 items, 1908-1998, pertains chiefly to persons in the arts and was compiled by William D. Eppes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library by William David Eppes of New York, New York, on December 8, 1997.
Biographical/Historical Information
William David Eppes, civic worker and writer, was born in Goodwater, Alabama, in 1918. He was educated at the Birmingham Conservatory of Music, William and Mary College, George Peabody College--Vanderbilt University, the University of Miami, the University of Manchester (England), Columbia University, New York University, and the University of Durham (England). Eppes was a founder of the Film Classics League, St. Petersburg, Florida; Backstage Gallery, St. Petersburg Junior College; and the Littlebury Eppes Memorial Library, Westover, Virginia. He served on the boards of St. Petersburg Symphony Orchestra and the Association of Village Homeowners (New York); Associates of Earl Greg Swem Library, William and Mary College; the Coral Gables Historic Preservation Board; and, the Greenwich Village Trust for Historic Preservation, Inc. He is also a member of the Theatre Historic Society; Authors' Guild, Inc.; The Drama League; and, the Society of the Descendants of Francis Eppes I of Virginia. Books authored by Eppes are: The Empire Theatre 1893-1953, Gertrude Michael - A Star of the Golden Age of Hollywood, and, Montgomery Theatre 1822- 1985.
Scope and Content Information
This collection of ca. 2310 items, 1908-1998, pertains chiefly to persons in the arts and was compiled by William D. Eppes. Eppes maintained autograph letters files which include correspondence, memorabilia, photographs, and printed material by or about persons in the fine arts, theatre, literary and political worlds. In the folder of William D. Eppes correspondence, there are lists of persons represented in this collection and Eppes' notes on portions of the collection. He also kept a file of printed obituaries and tributes to persons in the arts and other venues. Printed memorabilia includes playbills, programs, announcements, and poster replicas for theaters chiefly in New York City.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by subject.
Contents List
- Correspondence 1927-1998 (Box 1-4)
  - Correspondence: A 1937-1997 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: Ba-Be 1954-1995 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: J. Mitchell Baily (1945)1992 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: Tallulah Bankhead 1970-1994 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: Bi-By 1958-1997 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: C 1951-1997 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: D 1973-1994 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: E 1939-1997 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: Empire Theatre 1971-1987 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: Empire Theatre--History--"Charles Frohman's 'Lovely and Exciting Temple'--The Empire Theatre" 1978 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: Empire Theatre--History and Printed 1942-1981 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: Empire Theatre--Marquee 1977-1981 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: William D. Eppes 1980-1997 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: F 1963-1995 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Malcolm Forbes 1985-1990 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: 42nd Street Development Corporation 1985 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: G 1971-1997 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Ha 1937-1998 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Armand Hammer 1979-1990 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: He-Hu 1954-1994 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: J 1971-1997 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: K 1957-1996 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Anne Kaufman 1944(1971-1998), n.d., 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: L 1957-1997 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Landmarks Preservation Commission--Edna St. Vincent Millay House 1967-1979 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Landmarks Preservation Commission--Edna St. Vincent Millay House--Printed 1924-1994 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Eva LeGallienne 1953-1998 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Eva Le Gallienne--Photographs and Programs [1930s]-1979 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Eva Le Gallienne--Printed 1968-1997 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Eva Le Gallienne--Scrapbook, inscribed to William D. Eppes ca. 1926-1932 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Alfred Lunt 1987-1993 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: M 1958-1994 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: N 1962-1995 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: P-Q 1952-1997 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: R 1960-1994 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Sa-Si 1963-1997 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Sk-Sw 1957-1996 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Dorothy Stickney 1977-1998, n.d., 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: Dorothy Stickney--Photographs 1952, 1986-1995 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: Dorothy Stickney--Printed Articles 1927-1996, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: Dorothy Stickney--Research Collections 1987-1996 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: Dorothy Stickney--Theatre Programs and other memorabilia 1960-1990 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: T-U-V 1954-1997 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: Harry S. and Bess W. Truman 1970-1985 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: Wa-Wi 1908(1968-1997) (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: Wi-Wr 1957-1996 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: Y-Z 1953-1994 (Box 4)
- Printed Material 1939-1997 (Box 5-6)
  - Obituaries and Tributes: A 1966-1997 (Box 5)
  - Obituaries and Tributes: B 1979-1997 (Box 5)
  - Obituaries and Tributes: C 1982-1997 (Box 5)
  - Obituaries and Tributes: D-E 1982-1997 (Box 5)
  - Obituaries and Tributes: F 1978-1996 (Box 5)
  - Obituaries and Tributes: G 1984-1996 (Box 5)
  - Obituaries and Tributes: H 1982-1997 (Box 5)
  - Obituaries and Tributes: I-J-K 1988-1995 (Box 5)
  - Obituaries and Tributes: L 1977-1996 (Box 5)
  - Obituaries and Tributes: M 1982-1997 (Box 5)
  - Obituaries and Tributes: N-O 1985-1995 (Box 5)
  - Obituaries and Tributes: P-Q-R 1983-1995 (Box 5)
  - Obituaries and Tributes: S-T 1979-1996 (Box 5)
  - Obituaries and Tributes: U-Z 1983-1996 (Box 5)
  - Playbills 1939-1988, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Postcards n.d., 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Printed: Boothbay Theatre Museum Collection 1990 (Box 6)
  - Printed: 42nd Street Theatre 1977-1978 (Box 6)
  - Printed: Metropolitan Opera 1965-1986 (Box 6)
  - Printed: Metropolitan Opera Association 1969-1972 (Box 6)
  - Printed: New Orleans Opera 1973 (Box 6)
  - Printed: On Writers & Writing Desk Diaries, inscribed by Helen Sheehy 1992,1994 (Box 6)
  - Printed: Opera of Saint Louis 1984 (Box 6)
  - Printed: The Royal Ballet 1981 (Box 6)
  - Printed: The Ziegfeld Club, Inc. 1993 (Box 6)
  - Souvenir Program: Gone with the Wind1939 (Box 6)
  - Theatre Announcements and Posters 1984-1987, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Theatre Programs 1922-1928 (Box 6)
- Sound Recording 1942-1966, n.d.
  - "Selections from George Gershwin's Folk Opera 'Porgy and Bess' Volume Two." Includes leaflet of same title. Decca Records, Inc. Book-type cover. 1942, 3 sound discs; 10 in.; Phonodisc 0618
  - "Dorothy Stickney in 'A Lovely Light'," a dramatization by Dorothy Stickney of the poems and letters of Edna St. Vincent Millay as presented at the Hudson Theatre in New York City. Vanguard Recording Society, Inc. Inscribed by Dorothy Stickney. 1965, 2 sound discs; 12 in. Phonodisc 0619
  - "Opening Nights at the Met." Historic recordings of Metropolitan Opera stars re-creating their celebrated opening night roles. Limited Edition. Boxed set. RCA Victor. Includes booklet of same title, 50 pages. 1966, 3 sound discs; monaural; 12 in. Phonodisc 0620
  - "The Music of Cabin in the Sky featuring Ethel Waters." Liberty Music Shops. n.d., 3 sound discs; 10 in. Phonodisc 0621
  - "Presenting Gertrude Lawrence in Glamorous Music from 'Lady in the Dark.' Victor Records. Book-type cover. n.d., sound discs; 10 in. Phondisc 0622